

# **VINCENZO LO SCRUDATO**

# JUNIOR UX DESIGNER

# INFO & CONTACTS

Birth: 18/08/1991

Mobile: +39 3201771396

vincenzo.loscru@gmail.com

Linkedin: Vincenzo Lo Scrudato

Via Saccardo 44. Milano

# SUMMARY

I observe the world carefully, how it is changing and how people interact with it.

In my work I let myself be inspired by people, stories, ideas, cinema and technology.

In the world of Graphic Design I have learned to create creative solutions that give consistency to the product system.

The study of the relationship between people, the world and the productsystem introduced me to User Experience Design

# **GOALS AND PROJECTS**

 - 1° place Hackaton: Agos4Hack with EasyAgos at LUISSHub (27-28 Ottobre 2018)

# LANGUAGES

**ITALIAN** 

Mother tongue

**ENGLISH** 

**IELTS ACADEMIC: LEVEL B2** 

## OTHER INTEREST

Cinema, .photography, cook, bikes,all kind of music (but good ones).

#### MY UX MANIFESTO

#### 1. BEGIN WITH THE END IN MIND.

What is the most important KPI of your service? How this KPI can fit with the user need? This question prevent making decision based on only opinon

#### 2. COLLABORATION OVER SILOED WORKING.

Because UX sits at the intersection of user needs, technology constraints and business goals it really can't be anything other than a collaborative endeavour.

#### 3. UX WITHOUT USERS IS NOT UX.

As interaction Design Foundation says "user experience (UX) design is the process of creating products that provide meaningful and personally relevant experiences. This involves the careful design of both a product's usability and the pleasure consumers will derive from using it."

#### 4. UNDERSTAND AND PLAY WITH EMOTION.

Emotion is at the core of a user's experience. Consider a user's emotions when proposing a solution.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **JUNIOR UX DESIGNER**

ProntoPro.it (Gennaio 2019-Current), Milano

#### FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

**StudioRain (December 2017-September 2018), Palermo**Graphic designer per Ditancolor

#### **DIGITAL DESIGNER**

Anteria Srl (November 2017- February 2018), Palermo

UI Designer per Si24.it UI Designer per Anteria.eu

# **EDUCATION**

#### TAG INNOVATION SCHOOL

UX Design Master (2018), Milano

#### **ACADEMY OF FINE ARTS OF PALERMO**

Graphic Design (2014-2017), Palermo

-Tesi: Moving City Branding - Un mobile game come strumento di city branding

Autorizzo il trattamento dei miei dati personali ai sensi dell'art. 13 d. lgs. 30 giugno 2003 n°196 – "Codice in materia di protezione dei dati personali" e dell'art. 13 GDPR 679/16 – "Regolamento europeo sulla protezione dei dati personali".